Zilong (Ryan) Wang

 ♦ La Jolla, CA
 ☑ zlwang@ucsd.edu
 ♦ zlwang-cs.github.io

Research Interests

My research spans several areas of natural language processing, including reasoning, information extraction, multimodal learning, and language modeling. I primarily focus on LLM post-training, targeting at aligning LLMs to complex reasoning and planning with knowledge-intensive queries, autonomous agents, and mathematical problem-solving. Currently, I am exploring the collaboration of weak and strong LLMs and the process supervision with Monte Carlo Tree Search.

Education

University of California, San Diego

Oct. 2020 - Now

Ph.D. in Computer Science

o Advised by Prof. Jingbo Shang

Peking University

Sept. 2016 - Jun. 2020

B.S. in Computer Science

Outstanding Graduate of Beijing City and Peking University (Top 5%)

Experience

Amazon, Nile Foundation Team

Palo Alto, CA

Research Scientist Intern

Jun. 2024 - Now

• Working on efficient scaling up of process supervision on multi-step problem solving (e.g. agents, math reasoning).

Google Cloud AI Research & Google DeepMind

Remote

Student Researcher

Nov. 2023 - May 2024

• Working on reducing hallucinations and enhancing efficiency for retrieval augmented generation (RAG).

Google Cloud AI Research

Sunnyvale, CA

Student Researcher

Apr. 2023 - Sept. 2023

- Working on improving tabular reasoning ability of large language models through autonomous agents.
- The Chain-of-Table algorithm has been integrated into the products in Google Cloud.

Google DeepMind

Mountain View, CA

Student Researcher

Jun. 2022 - Sept. 2022

Working on multimodal information extraction and visually-rich document understanding (e.g. forms, receipts, structured documents).

Adobe Research, Document Intelligence Lab

Remote

Research Intern

Jun. 2021 - Sept. 2021

• Working on enabling language models to understand visual features from structured documents (e.g. forms, receipts, structured documents).

Publications

- Rising Rewards Elite Efficient Process Supervision in Automated Agent Training Zilong Wang, Jingbo Shang, Amazon Nile Foundation Model Team. (ongoing)
- 2. Speculative RAG: Enhancing Retrieval Augmented Generation through Drafting Zilong Wang, Zifeng Wang, Long Le, Huaixiu Steven Zheng, Swaroop Mishra, Vincent Perot, Yuwei Zhang, Anush Mattapalli, Ankur Taly, Jingbo Shang, Chen-Yu Lee, Tomas Pfister (preprint)
- 3. TableRAG: Million-Token Table Understanding with Language Models

Si-An Chen, Lesly Miculicich, Julian Martin Eisenschlos, Zifeng Wang, **Zilong Wang**, Yanfei Chen, Yasuhisa Fujii, Hsuan-Tien Lin, Chen-Yu Lee, Tomas Pfister

Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2024

4. Chain-of-Table: Evolving Tables in the Reasoning Chain for Table Understanding

Zilong Wang, Hao Zhang, Chun-Liang Li, Julian Martin Eisenschlos, Vincent Perot, Zifeng Wang, Lesly Miculicich, Yasuhisa Fujii, Jingbo Shang, Chen-Yu Lee, Tomas Pfister

The International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2024

5. OfficeBench: Benchmarking Language Agents across Multiple Applications for Office Automation

Zilong Wang, Yuedong Cui, Li Zhong, Zimin Zhang, Da Yin, Bill Yuchen Lin, Jingbo Shang (preprint)

6. LDB: A Large Language Model Debugger via Verifying Runtime Execution Step-by-step Li Zhong, Zilong Wang, Jingbo Shang

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2024 (ACL), 2024

7. Answer is All You Need: Instruction-following Text Embedding via Answering the Question Letian Peng, *Zilong Wang*, Feng Yao, Zihan Wang, Jingbo Shang Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (ACL), 2024

8. LMDX: Language Model-based Document Information Extraction and Localization

Vincent Perot, Kai Kang, Florian Luisier, Guolong Su, Xiaoyu Sun, Ramya Sree Boppana, **Zilong Wang**, Jiaqi Mu, Hao Zhang, Nan Hua

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2024 (ACL), 2024

9. Can ChatGPT replace StackOverflow? A Study on Robustness and Reliability of Large Language Model Code Generation

Li Zhong, Zilong Wang

The 38th Annual AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2023

10. Towards Zero-shot Relation Extraction in Web Mining: A Multimodal Approach with Relative XML Path

Zilong Wang, Jingbo Shang

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2023 (EMNLP), 2023

11. VRDU: A Benchmark for Visually-rich Document Understanding

Zilong Wang, Yichao Zhou, Wei Wei, Chen-Yu Lee, Sandeep Tata

Proc. of the 29th ACM SIGKDD Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining (KDD), 2023

12. MGDoc: Pre-training with Multi-granular Hierarchy for Document Image Understanding *Zilong Wang*, Jiuxiang Gu, Chris Tensmeyer, Nikolaos Barmpalios, Ani Nenkova, Tong Sun, Jingbo Shang and Vlad I. Morariu

Proc. of the 2022 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2022

13. Formulating Few-shot Fine-tuning Towards Language Model Pre-training: A Pilot Study on Named Entity Recognition

Zihan Wang, Kewen Zhao, Zilong Wang, Jingbo Shang

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2022 (EMNLP), 2022

14. Towards Few-shot Entity Recognition in Document Images: A Label-aware Sequence-to-Sequence Framework

Zilong Wang, Jingbo Shang

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: ACL 2022 (ACL), 2022

15. LayoutReader: Pre-training of Text and Layout for Reading Order Detection

Zilong Wang, Yiheng Xu, Lei Cui, Jingbo Shang, Furu Wei

Proc. of the 2021 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), 2021

16. DocStruct: A Multimodal Method to Extract Hierarchy Structure in Document for General Form Understanding

Zilong Wang, Mingjie Zhan, Xuebo Liu and Ding Liang

Findings of the Association for Computational Linguistics: EMNLP 2020 (EMNLP), 2020

17. Exploring Semantic Capacity of Terms

Jie Huang*, **Zilong Wang***, Kevin Chang, Wen-mei Hwu and JinJun Xiong Proc. of the 2020 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (**EMNLP**), 2020

Honors & Awards

- $\circ~2020\mbox{-}2021$ UCSD Powell Fellowship
- $\circ\,$ 2020-2021 UCSD Jacob School of Engineering Fellowship
- o 2020 Summa Cum Laude of Peking University (Top 5%)

Professional Service & Skills

Reviewer: ICLR, NeurIPS, ACL, EMNLP, NAACL, CVPR, ICML, COLM, COLING

Skills: Large language model reasoning and planning, reinforcement learning, DPO, PPO, multimodal data mining